Olaniyan, Olajide Adewale

Web & Applications Developer

+2348175981494 | jidd32@gmail.com | Lagos, Nigeria

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A prolific full stack software developer with 8+ years' experience in software development, IT networking and solution integration exercises. I have contributed to numerous software projects (businesses and non-profit applications) and network infrastructure projects with remarkable recognitions and awards. A music lover with a great flair for jazz. When doing nothing, I am with my guitar.

TECHNOLOGIES

Front End	CSS3, Bootstrap, HTML5, JavaScript, React.js, Vue.js
Back End	JavaScript, Java, Node.js, Ruby, Rails
Data Stores	PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL, Firebase
Web Servers	Apache Tomcat, Apache HTTP Server, Nginx, Microsoft IIS
Virtualization	Docker, Hyper-V
Operating Systems	Linux Red Hat, Ubuntu, Centos, Chromium OS, Mac OC, Windows 10, Windows Server, Linux Servers
Others	Git-workflow, Cisco routers, switches, UCM, call manages & wireless controllers, Nagios, Cacti

EXPERIENCE

Network Engineer | Pan Ocean Oil Corporation | Lagos, Nigeria December 2018 – Present

An indigenous oil and gas company and foremost to the Nation's total gas production

- Lead Network Engineer (network implementation for new locations and WAN integration)
- Leverage on coding skills to build a Proprietary Dashboard for the Enterprise Network Monitoring System
 Collating data from several sources
- Third level server administration support (Microsoft servers, Microsoft enterprise applications, Linux Server)
- <u>Technologies</u>: Cisco, Nagios, Ubuntu, Centos, Docker, Cacti, React, SQL, Node, Express, Shell Script, Office 365, Azure

Developer | Codergroups (Coderlist) | Remote

A website project with CMS for a London business

• Serve as the project user management developer to implement project database and database model and server as the

secondary backend engineer

- Technologies: Flexbox, HTML5, CSS3, Express, Node, Postgresql
- Link: https://ginnybradley.co.uk/

Web and Applications Developer | Timwe-Tech (Timwe Group) | Lagos, Nigeria September 2016 – December 2016

Provide a brief description of the company. For example: A global provider of tech solutions with a wide portfolio of products and services organized across software solutions, digital services, Fintech

Payphone application project with OSS and BSS integrations

- Implemented backend API using Java EE
- In charge of designing and editing project database using Navicat, PostgreSQL.
- Develop project history management with Elasticsearch, kibana and Fluent-d
- Technologies: Java EE, Postgresql, Navicat, Kibana, ElasticSearch, Fluent-d

Network Engineer | Pan Ocean Oil Corporation | Lagos, Nigeria December 2010 – 2016

An indigenous oil and gas company and foremost to the Nation's total gas production

- Overall responsibility for the management of Pan Ocean HQ and remote locations Datacenters
- Server administration (AD server, Microsoft Exchange server, O365 administration)
- Responsible for the implementation of network designs.
- Technical lead for management of enterprise-wide IP addressing, LAN, WAN and WLAN
- Configuration and setup of all new network modules (routers, switches, wireless controllers, access points, voice gateways, unified call managers)
- Active team member in creating IT infrastructure plan.
- Technical Focal point to IT service providers
- Network performance reporting (I developed the Nagios monitoring systems)
- Maintain communications uptime and availability
- Server administration (AD server, Microsoft Exchange server, O365 administration)
- Give expert advice for management consideration on major projects and technical matters involving IT theories, concepts and principles
- Train interns and lower level support staffs
- Technologies: Cisco, Nagios, Ubuntu, Asterisk, Microsoft Exchange,

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer - Member | Chingu Developers Cohorts | Remote May 2018 - Present

A global collaboration platform to build non-profit projects which are termed as voyages Projects:

Voyage 3 (Expense Tracking System with D3 for graphical rendering and ability to scan receipts)

• <u>Technologies</u>: React, Node, Express, Mongoose, D3

Voyage 8 (About to commence)

Developer | Stark Logic Limited (co-owned) | Lagos, Nigeria September 2018 – Present

A company with a vision to provide solutions that meet local needs

- Project sourcing and implementation
- Implement marketable proprietary ideas
- <u>Technologies</u>: React, WordPress, Mongo DB, HTML5, CSS,

EDUCATION

BSc Electronics & Electrical Engineering | Obafemi Awolowo University | Osun, Nigeria **2001 – 2007**

ADDITIONAL ACTIVITIES

VOLUNTEER (Care from Street kids) | Fair-Life Africa Foundation | Lagos, Nigeria

2015

PROFILES

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/olajide-olaniyan-ab0639134/

Twitter: https://twitter.com/mobell3
GitHub: https://github.com/jidemobell